Guide to the O.J. Simpson murder trial and DNA typing archive, 1988-1996.
Simpson, O.J. murder trial and DNA typing archive, 1988-1996.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
O.J. Simpson murder trial and DNA typing archive, 1988-1996.
53-12-3037
13.7 cubic ft.
Photocopies, printouts, clippings and video.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files of cases in which the use of DNA as evidence were an important factor, including the OJ Simpson trial.
Cornell University's Department of Science and Technology Studies conducted a National Science Foundation-supported research project: DNA Fingerprinting: Law and Science in Criminal Process. A supplemental project, conducted in 1995, and also supported by NSF created "An Archive of Material on the O.J. Simpson Murder Trial and DNA Typing." The goal of the archive was to collect and preserve ephemeral materials for studying popular constructions of credibility in science, especially on issues relating to genetics and DNA testing, and on the specific roles of the law and the media in shaping these constructions. The project's principal investigators were Sheila Jasanoff and Bruce Lewenstein. Graduate students included Saul E. Halfon and Simon A. Cole.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files of cases in which the use of DNA as evidence were an important factor, notably the People of New York State vs Castro, the case which set the precedent for allowing the use of DNA as evidence in a trial; photocopies, printouts, and clippings of news stories relating to the O.J. Simpson trial; interviews; and 235 Court TV tapes from the part of the Simpson trial in which the scientific evidence was provided.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cole, Simon A. (Simon Ablon), 1967-; Halfon, Saul E.; Jasanoff, Sheila.; Lewenstein, Bruce V.; Simpson, O. J., 1947---Trials, litigation, etc.; Cornell University. Dept. of Science & Technology Studies.; National Science Foundation (U.S.)
Subjects:
Trials (Murder)--California--Los Angeles.; Mass media and criminal justice.; Medical genetics--Law and legislation.; DNA fingerprinting--United States.; Forensic genetics--United States--Technique.; Criminals--United States--Identification.; Criminal investigation--United States--Technological innovations.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Miscellaneous
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Statutes (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guides to Experts by Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Case Opinions - Without Transcripts (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - DNA/Forensics Court Cases - Lists and Summaries (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - DNA Law Cases (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Transcripts by cases
  - State of Florida vs. Andrews (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Axwell vs. State of California (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - People of California vs. Halik (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - State of Delaware vs. Pennell (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - State of Florida vs. Wike (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wike vs. State of Florida (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Davidson vs. State of Indiana (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - State of Kansas vs. Smith (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - State of Minnesota vs. Bloom (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - State of New Jersey (NJ) vs. Williams (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  - State of Ohio vs. Blair (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - State of Ohio vs. Lee (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - State of Ohio (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - People of New York State (PNYS) vs. Larry Brown (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - PNYS vs. Castro (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - PNYS vs. Vann (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - PNYS vs. Wesley (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - PNYS vs. Keene (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - PNYS vs. White (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bethune vs. State of Texas (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - State of Texas vs. Davis (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - United States (US) vs. Yee (1) (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - US vs. Yee (2) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Spencer vs. Commonwealth of Virgina (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - State of Washington vs. Cauthron (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Yelder vs. State of Alabama (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - People (?) vs. Miles (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - State of (?) vs. Kelly (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jones vs. State of Florida (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - State of (?) vs. Thomas (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Newspaper stories
  - Simpson Case - Popular Lit. Articles (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Simpson Case - Newspaper Coverage (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Simpson Case - New York Times Coverage (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Blood/DNA Evidence, etc. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Coroner, Autopsy (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Lawyers/Personalities (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Race Issues, Police, Furman, etc. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Motive/Character Witness (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Pre-trial/Early Coverage (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Jury Related (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Simpson Case - NY Times - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Simpson Case - Editorials/Cartoons (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - Scientific Literature (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Time Coverage (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Simpson Book Reviews (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Excerpts from: In Contempt (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Interviews
  - Saul's Reports/Notes (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Case Interviews (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Interviews (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Lifecodes (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Nist: Dennis Reeder Interview (Box 2, Folder 29)
- DNA fingerprinting - miscellaneous
  - Works in Progress - DNA Fingerprinting (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Article Offprints (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sheila's DNA Group (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Law Reviews/Journal Articles, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Law Reviews/Journal Articles, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Law Reviews/Journal Articles, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Law Reviews/Journal Articles, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lempert Articles (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Cellmark (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - Longer Length (unpublished) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - Pre-OJ Popular Lit. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - DNA - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - FBI Related (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Resource Manual - FBI: Legal Aspects/DNA (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - BBI Porcedures (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - CACLD Related (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - Science Magazine - Letters/Articles (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - Newspaper Accounts (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - DNA Fingerprinting - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 48)
- DNA fingerprinting - specific case
  - Castro Opinion (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Castro - Volume 1 - Part 1 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Castro - Volume 1 - Part 2 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Castro - Volume 2 - pgs. 473-654 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Castro - Volume 2 - Part 2 - pgs 655-810 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Castro - Volume 3 - Part 3 - pgs 811-952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Castro - Volume 3 - Part 2 - pgs 953-1112 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Castro - Volume 4 - pgs 1113-1340 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Castro - Volume 5 - Part 1 - pgs 1341-1474 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Castro - Volume 5 - Part 2 - pgs 1475-1620 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Castro - Volume 6 - Part 1 - pgs 1621-1833 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Castro - Volume 6 - Part 2 - pgs 1834-2023 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Castro - Volume 7 - pgs 2024-2190 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Castro - Volume 8 - pgs 2190-2381 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Castro - Volume 9 - pgs 2381-2575A (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Castro - Volume 10 - pgs 2575-2691 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Castro - Volume 11 - pgs 2691-2820 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Castro - Volume 12 - pgs 2821-3006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Castro - Volume 13 - pgs 3007-3136 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Castro - Volume 14 - Part 1 - pgs 3136-3277 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Castro - Volume 14 - Part 2 - pgs 3278-3445 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Castro - Volume 15 - pgs 3446-3569 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Castro - Volume 16 - pgs 3570-3776 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Castro - Volume 16 - Part 2 - pgs 3777-3956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Castro - Volume 16 - Part 3 - pgs 3957-4090A (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Commentary on DNA Fingerprinting (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Legal Opinions (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Summaries of Symposiums on Novel Scientific Evidence (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Simpson Case - News Articles and Court Depositions from NET (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Computer Disks containing OJ Transcripts (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - OJ Trial Humor (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clips from the Boston Globe (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Articles about the Archive (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Products of the Archive: Papers by Cornell Faculty and Students, and Others (Box 4, Folder 10-18)
  - OJ Archive - Alec Jeffries Interview (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Simon Cole's Interview with Neufeld and Harmon (reports) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Simon Cole's Interviews (audio and floppy) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Trial Database (index of Simpson trial) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - OJ Archive - Ethnograph (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - OJ Archive - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - OJ Arhcive "Hungarian Bracelet" - Patrick Carey - Transcript Hearing Simpson Case (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Declarations of Experts on DNA Testing (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Summary of Cases and Articles in Motion to Exclude DNA Evidence (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Commentary with Judge Ito regarding Forensic Tests (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Motions from the Court on DNA Testing and Experts (Box 4, Folder 29)
- OJ Simpson case testimonies, defense motions, and miscellany
  - Testimony of Luper, Harper, and Fung; Apr. 3, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Testimony of Fung, Apr. 4-18, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 31-37)
  - Testimony of George Matheson, May 2-5, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "Blood Mix Hearing" - Testimony of Bruce Weir (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Index of Case Documents (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Defense Motions re: Blood Test Evidence (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Defense Reply re: Plaintiffs Motion to Preclude LAPD Testimony (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Defense Motion to Limit Cross-Exam of Dr. Kary Mullis (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Defense and Plaintiff Motions re: DNA Testing by CA Dept. of Just. Labs (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Plaintiff Motion to Exclude Evidence of Dr. Lee (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Memo re: Scheduling and Discovery of Forensic Testing (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Defense Emergency Motion for Sanctions re: Failure of Plaintiff to Disclose (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Defense Request for Production of Portions of Reference Samples (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Defense and Plaititff Motions on Excluding DNA Evidence (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Defense Order re: Marc Taylor's PRC Hybridization (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Defense Motion re: Kelly Hearing and Plaintiff's Response (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Opposition to Defense Request for Closure of DNA Hearing (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Freed, Donald and Raymond P. Briggs; Killing Time: The First Full Investigation. Macmillan, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- OJ video tapes
  - CNN Tapes (Box 6)
  - Numbered Excerpts #1-11, 14-20 (Box 6)
  - Numbered Excerpts #21-24 (Box 7)
  - Two Misc. Tapes (Box 7)
  - Court TV Tapes #1-31 (Box 7)
  - Court TV Tapes #33-66 (Box 8)
  - Court TV Tapes #67-100 (Box 9)
  - Court TV Tapes #101-134 (Box 10)
  - Court TV Tapes #135-168 (Box 11)
  - Court TV Tapes #169-202 (Box 12)
  - Court TV Tapes #203-235 (Box 13)
  - Court TV Tapes #236-242 (Box 14)
  - Four BBC Videotapes (Box 14)
  - Four Floppy Disks (Box 14)